The task is simple: walk or die.
The Long Walk is a science fiction, thriller, horror
film directed by Francis Lawrence.
In a dystopian near-future America, fifty teenage boys take part in a deadly annual walking contest,
forced to maintain a minimum pace or be executed, until only one survivor remains.
Raymond Garraty #47, played by Cooper Hoffman.
Peter McVries #23, played by David Jonsson.
Stebbins #38, played by Garrett Wareing.
Arthur Baker #6, played by Tut Nyuot.
Gary Barkovitch #5, played by Charlie Plummer.
Hank Olson #46, played by Ben Wang.
The Long Walk is a 2025 American dystopian survival thriller film
directed by Francis Lawrence and written by JT Mollner.
It is based on the 1979 novel by Stephen King.
The film stars Cooper Hoffman, David Jonsson, Garrett Wareing, Tut Nyuot, Charlie Plummer,
Ben Wang, Roman Griffin Davis, Josh Hamilton, Judy Greer, and Mark Hamill.
Set in a dystopian 1970s, the film follows fifty boys in an annually
televised competitive walking contest, meant to inspire viewers.
Each boy must maintain a pace of three miles per hour (4.8 km/h) of nonstop walking
for days, and failure to do so after three warnings results in death.
The boy who lasts the longest wins a large cash prize and
the fulfilment of one wish of his choice.
The Long Walk was released in the United States by
Lionsgate on September 12, 2025.
The film received positive reviews from critics, with the
performances of Hoffman and Jonsson receiving praise.
It grossed $63 million on a budget of $20 million.
The film explores themes of suicide, based on novel or
book, competition, dystopia, male friendship.
The tone is intense and dark and thought_provoking.